Saadat Ali

Ruby on Rails Developer

saadatali0202@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium Rawalpindi, Pakistan

+92 336 5910676

SUMMARY

Ruby on Rails Developer with experience in building full-stack applications and API in Ruby on Rails. Accomplishments Include:

- Built and deployed several applications using Heroku
- Tested various aspects of rails applications using RSpec (Request Specs, Model Specs, View Spec, and Routing specs)
- Worked in a group of four to complete a capstone project in 14 days as a Backend Engineer.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Rspec, Postgresql

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Docker, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, Jest, React Testing

Library, TDD, BDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote pair-programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Android Developer (Contract)

Remote, Rawalpindi, Pakistan December 2018 - September 2021

Hidden Space Browser — Internet Browser to implement the idea of downloading files that are not visible in the gallery.

Social Media Files Downloader — a small app where users can download files from social media platform links and view them only inside the app.

Remote

Flutter Freelance Developer

March 2021 - March 2022

JOCs — A dashboard-based cross-platform web application that helps customers to digitize their company and manage employees. (GitHub Link)

Ruby on Rails Projects

- Rails API for Hotel Reservations Capstone Project. (GitHub Link)
 - Work in Remote Pair-Programming with <u>Ivan Silva</u>
 - Testing using RSpec
 - Create Swagger Documentation
 - Use JWT for token authentication
 - Review pull requests of Front end team (<u>Front end Repository link</u>)
 - Deploy to Heroku
- Rails Full Stack Application called Saadat Blog. (GitHub Link)
 - Work in Pair Programming with <u>Blessed Jason Mwanza</u>
 - Testing using RSpec
 - Devise Authentication, CanCanCan Authorization
 - Deploy to Heroku
- Rails Full Stack Application called Budget App (GitHub Link)
 - Testing using RSpec
 - Devise Authentication, CanCanCan Authorization

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE January 2022 – August 2022

Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spending 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard GitFlow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Air University, Islamabad

September 2017 - July 2021

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

- Specialization in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning
- Gold Medal